<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dmso on Güngör Budak</title>
    <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/dmso/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dmso on Güngör Budak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 07:51:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/dmso/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DREAM Breast Cancer Sub-challenges</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/27/dream-breast-cancer-sub-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 07:51:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/27/dream-breast-cancer-sub-challenges/</guid>
      <description>I have been going over the sub-challenges before attempting to solve them. As I mentioned, there are three sub-challenges and somehow they are connected.
First, using given data and other possible data sources such as pathway databases, the causal signaling network of the phosphoproteins. There are 4 cell lines and 8 stimulus so they make total 32 networks at the end. Nodes are phosphoproteins and edges should be directed and causal (activator or inhibitor).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPN-DREAM Breast Cancer Network Inference Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/26/hpn-dream-breast-cancer-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 08:38:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/26/hpn-dream-breast-cancer-network/</guid>
      <description>Understanding signaling networks might bring more insights on cancer treatment because cells respond to their environment by activating these networks and phosphorylation reactions play important roles in these networks.
The goal of this challenge is to advance our ability and knowledge on signaling networks inference and protein phosphorylation dynamics prediction. Also, we are asked to develop a visualization method for the data.
The dataset provided is extensive and a result of RPPA (reverse-phase protein array) experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
