<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on Güngör Budak</title>
    <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on Güngör Budak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 03:58:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mann Whitney U Test (Wilcoxon Rank-Sum Test) Javascript Implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2016/01/16/mann-whitney-u-test-wilcoxon-rank-sum-test-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 03:58:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2016/01/16/mann-whitney-u-test-wilcoxon-rank-sum-test-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Currently Javascript is really poor in statistical methods compared to Python (SciPy) and R. There are several efforts to fill this gap, most notably from jStat. However, still many functions, distributions and tests are missing in this library. In one of my projects, I had to implement a Javascript version of Mann Whitney U test (or also called Wilcoxon rank-sum test). Here, I&amp;rsquo;m giving a link to its source code and describing how it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Impressions and Thoughts on Rosalind Project</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/04/first-impressions-and-thoughts-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 08:52:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/04/first-impressions-and-thoughts-on/</guid>
      <description>Actually, I signed up Rosalind.info 8 months ago, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really play around with it. But last week, in a BiGCaT science cafe, after I learnt it, I was more interested than before and I just started solving problems.
In each problem, you have a description about the context and also about the problem. Also, there is a sample input and output. Sometimes there are hints about the solution. What I did was to write a solution that works for the sample and hopefully for the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
