<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windows on Güngör Budak</title>
    <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windows on Güngör Budak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 05:08:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Install openpyxl on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2014/12/03/how-to-install-openpyxl-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 05:08:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2014/12/03/how-to-install-openpyxl-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>openpyxl is a Python library to read/write Excel 2007 xlsx/xlsm files. To download and install on Windows:
Download it from Python Packages
Then to install, extract the tar ball you downloaded, open up CMD, navigate to the folder that you extracted and run the following:
C:\Users\Gungor&amp;gt;cd Downloads\openpyxl-2.1.2.tar\dist\openpyxl-2.1.2\openpyxl-2.1.2 C:\Users\Gungor\Downloads\openpyxl-2.1.2.tar\dist\openpyxl-2.1.2\openpyxl-2.1.2&amp;gt;python setup.py install It&amp;rsquo;s going to install everything and will report any error. If there is nothing that seems like an error. You&amp;rsquo;re good to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Numpy Python Package on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2014/11/26/how-to-install-numpy-python-package-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 10:49:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2014/11/26/how-to-install-numpy-python-package-on/</guid>
      <description>Numpy (Numerical Python) is a great Python package that you should definitely make use of if you&amp;rsquo;re doing scientific computing
Installing it on Windows might be difficult if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how to do it via command line. There are unofficial Windows binaries for Numpy for Windows 32 and 64 bit which make it super easy to install.
Go to the link below and download the one for your system and Python version:http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Up Google Cloud SDK on Windows using Cygwin</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2014/03/16/set-up-google-cloud-sdk-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 19:17:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2014/03/16/set-up-google-cloud-sdk-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>Windows isn&amp;rsquo;t the best environment for software development I believe but if you have to use it there are nice softwares to make it easy for you. Cygwin here will help us to use Google Cloud tools but installation requires certain things that you should be aware of beforehand.
You&amp;rsquo;ll need
Python latest 2.7.x Google Cloud SDK Cygwin 32-bit (i.e. setup-x86.exe - note only this one works) openssh, curl and latest 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Convert PLINK Binary Formats into Non-binary Formats</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2014/02/24/how-to-convert-plink-binary-formats-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 11:28:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2014/02/24/how-to-convert-plink-binary-formats-to/</guid>
      <description>PLINK is a whole genome association analysis toolset and to save time and space, you need to convert your data files to binary formats (BED, FAM, BIM) but of course when you need to view the files, you have to convert them back to non-binary formats (PED, MAP) to be able to open them in your text editor such as Notepad on Windows OS.
This operation is really easy. It requires PLINK of course, and the following line of code written to DOS window (Run -&amp;gt; type cmd; hit ENTER) in the directory of PLINK:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
