<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bioinformatics on Güngör Budak</title>
    <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/bioinformatics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bioinformatics on Güngör Budak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 08:52:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/bioinformatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Impressions and Thoughts on Rosalind Project</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/04/first-impressions-and-thoughts-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 08:52:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/04/first-impressions-and-thoughts-on/</guid>
      <description>Actually, I signed up Rosalind.info 8 months ago, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really play around with it. But last week, in a BiGCaT science cafe, after I learnt it, I was more interested than before and I just started solving problems.
In each problem, you have a description about the context and also about the problem. Also, there is a sample input and output. Sometimes there are hints about the solution. What I did was to write a solution that works for the sample and hopefully for the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Online Tools for Teaching Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/27/using-online-tools-for-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 13:26:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/27/using-online-tools-for-teaching/</guid>
      <description>I attended one of science cafe meetings of BiGCaT group today and we discussed use of online tools for teaching bioinformatics.
Andra Waagmeester (PhD student form BiGCaT) introduced Rosalind Project as a teaching tool. This project mainly focuses on bioinformatics solutions. Various questions about bioinformatics are asked on the website. Actually, those are various problems that can be seen in any bioinformatics research and by solving them, it helps you learn bioinformatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPN-DREAM Breast Cancer Network Inference Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/26/hpn-dream-breast-cancer-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 08:38:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/26/hpn-dream-breast-cancer-network/</guid>
      <description>Understanding signaling networks might bring more insights on cancer treatment because cells respond to their environment by activating these networks and phosphorylation reactions play important roles in these networks.
The goal of this challenge is to advance our ability and knowledge on signaling networks inference and protein phosphorylation dynamics prediction. Also, we are asked to develop a visualization method for the data.
The dataset provided is extensive and a result of RPPA (reverse-phase protein array) experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dream Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/26/dream-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 06:43:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/26/dream-challenge/</guid>
      <description>This year, 8th Dream Challenge takes place and I will be working on this project as my internship job in BiGCaT, Bioinformatics, UM. The challenge brings scientists to catalyze the interaction between experiment and theory in the area of cellular network inference and quantitative model building in systems biology (as said on their webpage).
In this competition, I will work on a specific challenge about network modeling, dynamic response predictions and data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biyoinformatik mi? Yoksa Biyoenformatik mi?</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2012/03/18/biyoinformatik-mi-yoksa-biyoenformatik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 18:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2012/03/18/biyoinformatik-mi-yoksa-biyoenformatik/</guid>
      <description>Yazılarıma konu ararken kitaplarla birlikte interneti de karıştırıyorum. Yabancı kaynaklar elbette fazlaca var ve yeterliler, ancak Türkçe kaynaklara baktığımda ilk gözüme çarpan bu alanın isminin farklı kullanımları oldu.
Biliyorsunuz, İngilizcede bu alana bioinformatics deniyor. Gayet normal, çünkü İngilizcede informatics ics eki ile birlikte information sözcüğünden geliyor. Bu sözcük ise Latince kökene sahip1. Enformatik sözcüğü Türkçeye, Fransızcadan informatique sözcüğünden, enformatik olarak gelmiş, ayrıca bilişim olarak da Türkçesi önerilmiş2. Elbette bu Fransızca sözcük de İngilizcesi ile aynı kökene sahip.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
