<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data-derived network on Güngör Budak</title>
    <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/data-derived-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data-derived network on Güngör Budak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 10:10:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/data-derived-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last Submissions to the Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/09/02/last-submissions-to-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 10:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/09/02/last-submissions-to-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Today, I submitted in silico and experimental data network inference results on Synapse for the next leaderboard on this Wednesday.
For experimental part, I had to exclude edges with FGFR1 and FGFR3 because the data lacks phosphorylated forms of these proteins and networks must be constructed using only phosphoproteins in the data.
Since there was an update for in silico part, I had to modify the script and resubmit the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Visualization Using Cytoscape</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/29/network-visualization-using-cytoscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 10:32:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/29/network-visualization-using-cytoscape/</guid>
      <description>Cytoscape is a nice tool to visualize network for better understanding and delivery. I used it for in silico data network visualization and the result was really pretty. Now, I have networks constructed using experimental data from HPN-DREAM Challenge.
In this post, I want to demonstrate how to visualize a network with scores. I&amp;rsquo;m using Cytoscape 2.8 on Ubuntu 12.
First, the network will be read from a SIF file which is default format of Cytoscape for networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting Expression Curves for Experimental Data</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/27/plotting-expression-curves-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 11:08:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/27/plotting-expression-curves-for/</guid>
      <description>As I can plot expression curves for in silico data. I moved on experimental data which is more complex and larger. This data is the result of RPPA experiments on different breast cancer cell lines and it includes protein abundance measurements for about 45 phophoproteins. These phosphoproteins are treated with different inhibitors and stimuli and by comparing their expressions, I will try to infer relations between them.
Before moving on inferring part, I want to have a script that can plot the graphs so that I can see particular results for specific cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In silico Network Inference Last Improvements and Visualization of Result in Cytoscape</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/12/in-silico-network-inference-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 09:48:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/12/in-silico-network-inference-last/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m almost done with the analysis of in silico data, although I need to decide if I need further analysis with the inhibiting parent nodes in the network. Last, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t filter out duplicate edges, which were scored differently. Now, with some improvements in the script, low scores duplicates are filtered and there is a better final list of edges which is ready to be visualized.
I also tried visualizing it on Cytoscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting Expression Profiles Data Analysis for Network Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/24/plotting-expression-profiles-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 09:17:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/24/plotting-expression-profiles-data/</guid>
      <description>For in silico data network inference I decided to develop a script because the existing tools have bugs and they are not compatible with the data. At the same time, I will try to report bugs and the compatibility issues to developers.
in silico data has 660 experiment results of 20 antibodies, 4 kinds of stimuli and 3 kinds of inhibitors. Antibodies are treated with a stimulus, say at t_0 and in the case of inhibitors, say at t_i, antibodies are pre-incubated for some time (t_pre) and then, treated with a stimulus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Inference Challenge in silico Data</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/18/network-inference-challenge-in-silico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 07:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/18/network-inference-challenge-in-silico/</guid>
      <description>I had a meeting with BiGCaT this week and we discussed DREAM Breast Cancer Challenge. I presented the challenge and also some ways that I have found to solve the first sub-challenge network inference. Tina, from BiGCaT, suggested starting with in silico data which is much simpler than breast cancer data. Later, I can use the methods I develop for in silico data in experimental data.
in silico data contains 20 antibodies, 3 inhibitors and 2 ligand stimuli with 2 different concentration for each.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
