<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>biology on Güngör Budak</title>
    <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in biology on Güngör Budak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 08:52:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First Impressions and Thoughts on Rosalind Project</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/04/first-impressions-and-thoughts-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 08:52:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/04/first-impressions-and-thoughts-on/</guid>
      <description>Actually, I signed up Rosalind.info 8 months ago, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really play around with it. But last week, in a BiGCaT science cafe, after I learnt it, I was more interested than before and I just started solving problems.
In each problem, you have a description about the context and also about the problem. Also, there is a sample input and output. Sometimes there are hints about the solution. What I did was to write a solution that works for the sample and hopefully for the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving Data with AJAX using jQuery, PHP and MySQL</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/28/retrieving-data-with-ajax-using-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 18:04:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/28/retrieving-data-with-ajax-using-jquery/</guid>
      <description>Last semester, I took a course from Informatics Institute at METU called &amp;ldquo;Biological Databases and Data Analysis Tools&amp;rdquo; where first we learned what is a database and how to do queries on it. Also, the technology behind databases are taught. Then, we learned many biological databases and data analysis tools available. These include gene, protein and pathway databases, tools for creating databases.
As a final project, we were asked to create an online tool that can search a database and get the data and display it on any web browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
