<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>macos on Güngör Budak</title>
    <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/macos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in macos on Güngör Budak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 11:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Easy and Free Method to Compress Images on macOS with GUI and Terminal</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2018/10/11/easy-and-free-method-to-compress-images-on-macos-with-gui-and-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2018/10/11/easy-and-free-method-to-compress-images-on-macos-with-gui-and-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Image compression is mostly needed if you are short of storage on your devices or if you want to serve your images online and you want to optimize them in a way that we load fast which greatly affects how search engines evaluates your content and how users will enjoy your website.
This is especially important if you are also aiming to support for mobile devices and internet connections that are relatively slow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Leak Testing with Valgrind on macOS using Docker Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2018/06/13/memory-leak-testing-with-valgrind-on-macos-using-docker-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 10:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2018/06/13/memory-leak-testing-with-valgrind-on-macos-using-docker-containers/</guid>
      <description>I had some issues installing Valgrind on macOS High Sierra and [posted some tips to successfully install it to the system]({% post_url 2018-04-28-how-to-install-valgrind-on-macos-high-sierra %}). Although I could install the software this way, it didn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly after testing with with several real and dummy C++ codes. It was giving me a memory leak error even with an empty code. So, then I decided to use an Ubuntu 16.04 based Docker container to test the code within the container using the Ubuntu version of Valgrind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Valgrind on macOS High Sierra</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2018/04/28/how-to-install-valgrind-on-macos-high-sierra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2018/04/28/how-to-install-valgrind-on-macos-high-sierra/</guid>
      <description>Valgrind is a programming tool for memory debugging, memory leak detection and profiling. Its installation for macOS High Sierra seems problematic and I wanted to write this post to tell the solution that worked for me. I use Homebrew to install it which is the recommended way and the solution also uses it.
So, when you try installing right away, you may get the following error:
brew install valgrind valgrind: This formula either does not compile or function as expected on macOS versions newer than Sierra due to an upstream incompatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
