<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>in silico on Güngör Budak</title>
    <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/in-silico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in in silico on Güngör Budak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 10:10:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/tag/in-silico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last Submissions to the Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/09/02/last-submissions-to-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 10:10:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/09/02/last-submissions-to-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Today, I submitted in silico and experimental data network inference results on Synapse for the next leaderboard on this Wednesday.
For experimental part, I had to exclude edges with FGFR1 and FGFR3 because the data lacks phosphorylated forms of these proteins and networks must be constructed using only phosphoproteins in the data.
Since there was an update for in silico part, I had to modify the script and resubmit the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Experimental Data from Network Inference Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/14/working-with-experimental-data-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 05:48:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/14/working-with-experimental-data-from/</guid>
      <description>As I almost finished with in silico data, I moved on to analyses of experimental data using the same script. But since the characteristics of data is somehow different, before inferring network, I need to modify the script to be able to read experimental data files.
These differences include missing data values for some conditions. This makes analyses difficult because I have to estimate a value for them and this will decrease the confidence score of edges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In silico Network Inference Last Improvements and Visualization of Result in Cytoscape</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/12/in-silico-network-inference-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 09:48:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/12/in-silico-network-inference-last/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m almost done with the analysis of in silico data, although I need to decide if I need further analysis with the inhibiting parent nodes in the network. Last, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t filter out duplicate edges, which were scored differently. Now, with some improvements in the script, low scores duplicates are filtered and there is a better final list of edges which is ready to be visualized.
I also tried visualizing it on Cytoscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring Edges Network Inference HPN-DREAM Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/02/scoring-edges-network-inference-hpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 08:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/02/scoring-edges-network-inference-hpn/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I managed to infer a network for some part of in silico data from the challenge. Since the challenge also asks for scoring the edges in networks, I developed the script further and add a function for that.
edgeScorer function gets data object of average time points for each curve in intervention/no-intervention sets and scores each edge for each set of conditions. For this, first, it looks for the largest difference among the sets and set it as maxDifference and later, it stores differences divided by maxDifference in another data object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining Edges More Progress on Network Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/01/determining-edges-more-progress-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 09:42:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/08/01/determining-edges-more-progress-on/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I have been writing an R script to infer network using in silico data. Last version of the script was reading MIDAS file and plotting expression profiles. I have modified it and now it reads MIDAS file, does some analyses and prints causal relations to a file. This file is a SIF file as required.
This dataset is generated with 20 antibodies but only 3 of them are perturbed. Also, for one, stimulus is missing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting Expression Profiles Data Analysis for Network Inference</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/24/plotting-expression-profiles-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 09:17:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/24/plotting-expression-profiles-data/</guid>
      <description>For in silico data network inference I decided to develop a script because the existing tools have bugs and they are not compatible with the data. At the same time, I will try to report bugs and the compatibility issues to developers.
in silico data has 660 experiment results of 20 antibodies, 4 kinds of stimuli and 3 kinds of inhibitors. Antibodies are treated with a stimulus, say at t_0 and in the case of inhibitors, say at t_i, antibodies are pre-incubated for some time (t_pre) and then, treated with a stimulus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Inference Challenge in silico Data</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/18/network-inference-challenge-in-silico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 07:59:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/18/network-inference-challenge-in-silico/</guid>
      <description>I had a meeting with BiGCaT this week and we discussed DREAM Breast Cancer Challenge. I presented the challenge and also some ways that I have found to solve the first sub-challenge network inference. Tina, from BiGCaT, suggested starting with in silico data which is much simpler than breast cancer data. Later, I can use the methods I develop for in silico data in experimental data.
in silico data contains 20 antibodies, 3 inhibitors and 2 ligand stimuli with 2 different concentration for each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress on Network Inference Sub-Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/02/progress-on-network-inference-sub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 10:13:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/07/02/progress-on-network-inference-sub/</guid>
      <description>This sub-challenge has several requirements:
Directed and causal edges on the models (32 models - 4 cell lines × 8 stimuli) Edges should be scored (normalizing to range between 0 and 1) that will show confidence Nodes will be phosphoproteins from the data Prior knowledge network (that can be constructed using pathway databases) is allowed to be used (actually this is a must for some network inference tools) First thing was to look for existing tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPN-DREAM Breast Cancer Network Inference Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/26/hpn-dream-breast-cancer-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 08:38:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gungorbudak.com/blog/2013/06/26/hpn-dream-breast-cancer-network/</guid>
      <description>Understanding signaling networks might bring more insights on cancer treatment because cells respond to their environment by activating these networks and phosphorylation reactions play important roles in these networks.
The goal of this challenge is to advance our ability and knowledge on signaling networks inference and protein phosphorylation dynamics prediction. Also, we are asked to develop a visualization method for the data.
The dataset provided is extensive and a result of RPPA (reverse-phase protein array) experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
